Donald Barthelme Literary Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Donald Barthelme Literary Papers
1956-2001
Barthelme, Donald
29 boxes
2002-007
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Donald Barthelme was an experimental short story writer and novelist who contributed frequently to The New Yorker magazine in the 1960s, 1970s, and 1980s. He remains best known for his classic collection Sixty Stories. Barthelme served as director of the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston for many years. The collection contains typescript drafts, galley proofs, and page proofs of Barthelme's work, correspondence with fellow writers, and other materials related to Barthelme's writing and teaching career.
Biographical Note
Donald Barthelme was born in Philadelphia in 1931 to parents Donald Barthelme Sr. and Helen (Bechtold) Barthelme. In 1932, the family moved to Houston, where Donald Barthelme Sr. developed an architectural practice and taught at the University of Houston and Rice University. Barthelme had four younger siblings: Joan (born 1932), Peter (born 1938), Frederick (born 1943), and Steven (born 1947).
Barthelme enrolled at the University of Houston in 1949, where he took courses in journalism, literature, creative writing, and philosophy. He became a reporter, critic, and editor for the school's newspaper, The Cougar.
In July 1951, he left the University of Houston for a job at the Houston Post, where he reviewed movies, plays, and concerts. From July 1953 to December 1954 he served in Korea, writing for the 2nd Infantry Division's official publication. Following his return to Houston, Barthelme took a public relations job at the University of Houston. There he founded and became editor of the interdisciplinary journal Forum. In 1961, Barthelme became acting director of the Contemporary Arts Museum. The following year he moved to New York City to edit a new journal of art and literature called Location.
In 1961, Barthelme's short story "The Darling Duckling at School" (later renamed "Me and Mrs. Mandible") appeared in the journal Contact. Inspired by Samuel Beckett, Barthelme rejected the constraints of traditional plot, setting, and character development in favor of verbal collages full of absurdity and wit. In 1963, Barthelme published the story "L'lapse" in the New Yorker, quickly becoming a regular contributor.
In 1964 Barthelme released his first collection of stories, Come Back, Dr. Caligari. From that point on, he stayed at the forefront of American literature for three decades. Barthelme published nine more story collections, and 129 stories and "casuals" in the New Yorker. Always innovative, he created "collage stories" that combined images and text, and "dialogue stories" in which two disembodied voices alternate in conversation. He also published three novels - Snow White, The Dead Father, and Paradise. In 1972 he released a children's book, The Slightly Irregular Fire Engine, winning the National Book Award for Children's Literature.
Barthelme remains best known for Sixty Stories, a 1981 anthology of his finest work from the sixties and seventies. Sixty Stories was nnominated for the National Book Critics Circle Award, the PEN/Faulkner Award for Fiction, and the Los Angeles Times Book Prize in 1982.
Donald Barthelme taught creative writing at City College in New York from 1974-75. In 1979, he was invited to teach in the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston. Initially he taught in Houston one semester a year, while continuing to live in New York City. In 1983, Barthelme moved to Houston to become a full-time professor. A beloved teacher, he eventually became director of the Creative Writing Progam, a position he held until his death.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains typescript drafts, galley proofs, and page proofs of Donald Barthelme's novels, collected works, short stories, and other writings, plus collages and collage stories created by Barthelme. One of the richest aspects of the collection is the large set of letters and cards from Barthelme's writing friends and colleagues. The collection also includes about a dozen photographs of Barthelme. In addition, material related to Barthelme's teaching career is incorporated, notably student works that Barthelme received during his years in the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston.
Each series is prefaced by a detailed description.
Index Terms
Terms are either Library of Congress Subject Headings or taken from local sources.
Subjects (Persons)
Angell, Roger; Barth, John, 1930-; Barthelme, Donald; Beattie, Ann; Hijuelos, Oscar; Lowry, Beverly.; Paley, Grace; Percy, Walker, 1916-1990; Powell, Padgett
Subjects
Authors, American--20th century; Experimental fiction, American; Postmodernism (Literature)--United States
Formats
Correspondence; Typescripts; Page proofs; Galley proofs
Acquisition
This collection was acquired in 2002 from Marion Barthelme.
A few miscellaneous items already owned by the University of Houston Libraries were added to the collection. Typescripts of the short stories "City Life," "City Life II," and "A Dream" were purchased from Joseph the Provider Books in the 1980s. Four typescripts of Donald Barthelme's Paris Review interview, one proof sheet of the interview introduction, and letters from George Plimpton and J.D. O'Hara were also purchased from Joseph the Provider Books in the 1980s. A speech on writers delivered at University of Houston in 1974 was purchased from Detering Book Gallery in 1979. The non-fiction piece "Woman is an imaginary being" was transferred from the Donald Barthelme Forum Collection. The Houston Chronicle article "Donald Barthelme: Serious Writer at Play" was donated by Michael Berryhill in 2005.
Related Material
The University of Houston Libraries also hold the Donald Barthelme Forum Collection. This collection contains three boxes of materials related to Barthelme's tenure as editor of the University of Houston's interdisciplinary journal Forum from 1956-1960.
Open for research.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Works by Barthelme [1959]-1990
  Novels and Collected Works, 1970-1990
  This series traces the preparatory stages for Barthelme's published works, which were primarily collections of short stories or novels. The material related to a single work may include typescripts, page layouts, galley proofs, page proofs, dust jackets, and other formats. Materials are arranged in order of their production, beginning with typescripts and ending with dust jackets. Some of the short story collections include bound volumes which collected typescripts, photocopied drafts, and the printed pages of previously published stories together. Prior to 1975, Barthelme rarely kept early drafts of his work.
  - Amateurs, 1976
    - Copyedited typescript, photocopied, and printed pages, with corrections (bound) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Title page layout (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Galley proofs, with corrections (Box 24)
    - Page proof, partial (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - City Life, 1970
    - Carbon copy of typescript and printed pages, with corrections (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Copyedited typescript and printed pages, with corrections (bound) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Paste up (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Page proofs, author's, photocopied, with corrections (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Page proofs, printer's, with artwork (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Dead Father, 1975
    - Early typescript, photocopied (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Typescript with corrections, with note (bound) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Typescript, photocopied, with corrections (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Layout pages, with partial photocopied typescript (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Copyedited typescript, photocopied, with corrections (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Page proofs, uncut (Box 24)
    - Dust jacket (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Forty Stories, 1987
    - Table of contents (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Typescript, photocopied, and printed pages, with corrections (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
    - Typescript, photocopied, and printed pages, with additions and corrections (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    - Typescript, photocopied, and printed pages (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Dust jacket (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Great Days, 1979
    - Copyedited typescript, photocopied, and printed pages, with corrections; with layout and dust jacket (bound) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Galley proofs (Box 24)
    - Galley proofs (Box 24)
    - Dust jacket (Box 2, 13)
  - Guilty Pleasures, 1974
    - Copyedited printed, typescript, and photocopied pages with corrections; with title page layout (bound) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Galley proofs, photocopied (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Camera-ready copy for Delta Edition (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Camera-ready copy for Delta Edition (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The King, 1990
    - Earlier typescript (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Earlier typescript (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Various typescripts and partial typescripts (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
    - Later typescript (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Copyedited typescript, photocopied, with corrections by Frederick Barthelme, with letter from Frederick Barthelme to Kathy Banks of Harper & Row, August 27, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Final typescript in black folder (two) (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Typescript for readings (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Woodcuts for art research? (photocopies) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Layout with original artwork (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Artwork (photocopies) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Galley proof, photocopies, with note (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Overnight to Many Distant Cities, 1983
    - Typescript, including photocopies, with corrections (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Typescript, photocopied, and printed pages, with corrections [mostly from Sixty Stories and Overnight to Many Distant Cities] (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Paradise, 1986
    - Typescript pages, with note from Donald Barthelme (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Early typescript (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Early typescript, photocopied, with corrections (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
    - Early typescript, photocopied (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Early typescript, photocopied, with new dedication (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
    - Final typescript (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Corrections for typesetter (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Corrections for typesetter (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Copyedited typescript (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
    - Galley proofs, author's (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Galley proofs, printer's (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Galley proof (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Page proof, author's (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Page proof, author's (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Page proof, printer's, 5/21/86 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Page proof, printer's, 5/21/86 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Page proof, printer's, 6/26/86 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - Page proof, final (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Dust jacket (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Presents, 1980
    - Page proofs, with corrections (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Sadness, 1972
    - Dust jacket (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sam's Bar, 1987
    - Typescript draft, photocopied (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Typescript draft, alternate, photocopied (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Introduction, storyboards, and loose pages, with correspondence from Seymour Chwast (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Draft with inserted text (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Page proofs, with corrections (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sixty Stories, 1981
    - Copyedited typescript, photocopied, and printed pages, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 5-8)
    - Galley proofs, author's (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
    - Galley proofs, printer's (Box 6, Folder 12-14)
    - Page proofs (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Page proofs (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Page proofs, author's (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Page proofs, printer's, 4/13/81 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Page proofs, printer's, 5/27/81 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    - Page proofs, printer's, 6/10/81 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - Dust jacket (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Snow White, 1967
    - Copyedited typescript with corrections (bound) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Unspeakable Practices, Unnatural Acts, 1968
    - Copyedited photocopied and printed pages, with correspondence from Jane Bierhorst (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Page proofs (Box 25)
    - Page proofs, author's, with corrections (Box 25)
  Short Stories, [1959]-1987
  This series includes short stories in manuscript or typescript form. Barthelme rarely kept early drafts of his work, so many of these stories are in a finished or nearly finished stage and show minimal editing by the author. Some galley proofs, tear sheets, and paste ups are also included.
  - The Abduction from the Seraglio, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Adventure, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Affection, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Agreement, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Typescript, photocopied (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Tear sheet, photocopied (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Alice, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Among the Beanwoods/The Beanwoods[unpublished], undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Apology, 1978
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Aria, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Art of Baseball, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Author, 1987
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The Balloon, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Basil from her Garden, 1985
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Galley proof (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Bishop, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Bluebeard, 1986
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Page proof (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Brain Damage, undated
    - Typescript (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Paste up (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Captain Blood, [1979] (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - The Captured Woman, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - The Catechist, [1971] (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Chablis, 1983
    - Typescript, photocopy (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Challenge, 1981
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Galley proof (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - City Life, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - City Life II, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - A City of Churches, undated
    - Typescript (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Paste up (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Concerning the Bodyguard, 1978
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Construction, 1985
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Galley proof (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Conversations with Goethe, 1980
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Cornell, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Cortes and Montezuma, 1977
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Paste up (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - The Crisis, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Critique de la Vie Quotidienne, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - The Dassaud Prize, 1976
    - Page proof (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Daumier, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Departures, [1971] (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - The Director, undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - The Discovery, undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - The Dolt, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - The Dolt, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - A Dream, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Edward and Pia, undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Edward and Pia, undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Edwards, Amelia, photocopied, undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - The Emperor, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Eugenie Grandet, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - The Explanation, undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - The Extremely Large Cheese (carbon copy), undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - The Falling Dog, undated (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - The Farewell Party, undated (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - A Few Moments of Sleeping and Waking, undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - A Film, 1970
    - Typescript (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - The Fireman, undated (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Florence Green is 81, undated (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Flying to America, undated (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - The Foolfarm Report, undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Game, undated (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - The Genius, undated (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Grandmother's House, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Great Days, undated (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - The Great Debate, 1976
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Heroes, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - How I Write My Songs, 1978
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - I Bought a Little City, undated
    - Typescript (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - The Inauguration
    - Tear sheet, undated (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - January, 1987
    - Typescript (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Galley proof (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Jaws, undated (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Kierkegaard Unfair to Schlegel, undated (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - The King of Jazz, 1976
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Paste up (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Kissing the President, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - The Leap, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Letters to the Editore, undated (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Lightning, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - A Man, undated (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Man's Face, undated
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Manual for Sons, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Margins, undated (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Marie, Marie, Hold on Tight, undated (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Momma, 1978
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Monumental Folly (with Edward Sorel), undated
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - More Zero, 1986
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Morning, 1978
    - Typescripts (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Tear sheet (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - The Mothball Fleet, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Natural History, undated
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The New Member, [1974] (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The New Music, 1978
    - Typescripts (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The New Owner, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - A Note on Angels, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Nothing: A Preliminary Account, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - One Hundred Ten West Sixty-First Street, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - On the Deck, 1986
    - Typescript (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Galley proofs (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - On the Steps of the Conservatory, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Opening, 1984
    - Typescripts (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Our Work and Why We Do It, 1973
    - Typescript (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Overnight to Many Different Cities, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Pages from the Annual Report, [1959] (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Typescript (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Paradise (Before the Egg Broke), undated
    - Galley proof, with note (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Paraguay, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - The Party, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Pepperoni, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Perpetua, [1971] (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - The Phantom of the Opera's Friend, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Philadelphia, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - The Photographs, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - The Piano Player, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - The Policemen's Ball, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Pool [unpublished], undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Presents, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - The Question Part, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Rebecca, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Recitative [unpublished?], undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Report, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Return, [1984] (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - The Rise of Capitalism, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Rough Draft [unpublished?], undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Sakrete, 1983
    - Typescript (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - The School, undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Sentence, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - A Shower of Gold, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Simon, 1984
    - Typescripts (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Sindbad, 1984
    - Typescripts (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Snap Snap, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Some of Us Had Been Threatening Our Friend Colby, [1973] (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - The Story Thus Far, undated
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Subpoena, undated (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Swallowing, [1972]
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Tales of the Swedish Army, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - The Teachings of Don B.: A Yankee Way of Knowledge (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Typescript, (carbon copy), undated
    - Tear sheet, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - The Temptation of St. Anthony, undated (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Terminus, undated (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Thailand, undated (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - That Cosmopolitan Girl, undated (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - This Newspaper Here, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Three Great Meals, 1987
    - Typescripts (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Tickets, undated (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - To London and Rome, undated
    - Paste up (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Untitled ("Benjamin Ziff..."), undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Views of My Father Weeping, undated (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Visitors, 1981
    - Typescript (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Wasteland! (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - We Hope You'll Be Very Happy Here (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Well We All Had Our Willie and Wade Records..., undated
    - Typescript (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Galley proof (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Page proof (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - What To Do Next, 1973
    - Tear sheet (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Report, undated (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - The Wound, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Wrack 1972 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - You are as Brave as Vincent Van Gogh (photocopy), 1977 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - You are Cordially Invited [unpublished], undated (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - The Zombies, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Fragments, undated
    - "...canned goods..." (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - The Donkey Prince (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - Elise has cancer... (Box 9, Folder 86)
    - Hamlet's Ghost... (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - In a country under the sea... (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Just before he died, Heidegger... (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - Moving (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - The skeleton in the closet... (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - Tell me everything... (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Then I dreamed...magic show... (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - Untitled Collage Story (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - Untitled (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - Varieties of Outcry [collage story] (Box 9, Folder 96)
    - Well C.T. got back here... (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - The World Almanac and Book of Facts, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - You must take my course... (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Fragments, miscellaneous, undated (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Fragments, Tear sheets, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Proofs, The New Yorker, 1964-1987 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  Plays, 1974-1999
  Typescripts and other materials related to plays by Donald Barthelme or adapted from his work.
  - The Conservatory, undated
    - Typescript, photocopied (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The Emerald [teleplay], [1981]
    - Typescript (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Typescript with letter from Harrison Starr (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Emerald, adaptation by Adam Greenfield, 1999
    - Typescript, photocopied, in folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Friends of the Family, undated
    - Typescript, photocopied (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Great Days, [1983]
    - Typescript (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Typescript, photocopied (American Place Theatre) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Typescript, photocopied (American Place Theatre), with corrections, in folder (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Typescript, photocopied (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Set design (Box 29)
    - Programs; layout for program, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Snow White, A Play with Music, 1974